[
  {
    "number": 1,
    "question": "Which of the following is a qualier for the diagnoses under the disruptive and dissocial disorders grouping?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Emotional lability",
      "B": "Childhood vs adult onset",
      "C": "Criminal behaviour",
      "D": "Limited prosocial emotions",
      "E": "Self-injury"
    },
    "correct_answer": "D",
    "explanation": "The disruptive and dissocial disorders diagnostic grouping includes oppositional defiant disorder and conduct disorder. They can both receive a qualier of 'limited prosocial emotions' that indicates a poorer long-term prognosis."
  },
  {
    "number": 2,
    "question": "Which of the following is a qualier, an additional diagnostic descriptor, that can be used for disorders under the obsessive-compulsive and related disorders grouping?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Prominent checking behaviours",
      "B": "Without obsessive ideation",
      "C": "Poor to absent insight",
      "D": "Treatment resistant",
      "E": "Without compulsive behaviours"
    },
    "correct_answer": "C",
    "explanation": "The poor to absent insight qualier can be used when an individual's obsessive cognitions are so intense as to be almost delusional in nature, but they are consistent with the existing obsessive-compulsive or related disorder diagnosis."
  },
  {
    "number": 3,
    "question": "Which of the following disorders is included in the new diagnostic grouping of disorders of bodily distress and bodily experience in ICD-11?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Trichotillomania",
      "B": "Body integrity dysphoria",
      "C": "Hypochondriasis",
      "D": "Body dysmorphic disorder",
      "E": "Excoriation disorder"
    },
    "correct_answer": "B",
    "explanation": "The diagnostic grouping of disorders of bodily distress and bodily experience includes bodily distress disorder and body integrity dysphoria, which is characterised by the desire to have a certain disability."
  },
  {
    "number": 4,
    "question": "Which of the following diagnostic groupings includes selective mutism in ICD-11?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Anxiety and fear-related disorders",
      "B": "Neurodevelopmental disorders",
      "C": "Dissociative disorders",
      "D": "Obsessive-compulsive and related disorders",
      "E": "Disorders specifically associated with stress"
    },
    "correct_answer": "A",
    "explanation": "Anxiety and fear-related disorders includes selective mutism and separation anxiety."
  },
  {
    "number": 5,
    "question": "Body integrity dysphoria is a new inclusion in ICD-11. Which of the following is characteristic of this new disorder?",
    "options": {
      "A": "The feeling that a body part is not truly part of one's body",
      "B": "The sense that one's body is not real",
      "C": "The desire to have a specific disability",
      "D": "The sense that one's body is not functioning correctly",
      "E": "The feeling that a certain body part is not under one's control"
    },
    "correct_answer": "C",
    "explanation": "Body integrity dysphoria is characterised by the desire to have a particular disability and to feel discomforted by not having this disability."
  },
  {
    "number": 6,
    "question": "In ICD-11, which of the following diagnoses is still recognised in the schizophrenia and primary psychotic disorders diagnostic grouping?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Hebephrenic schizophrenia",
      "B": "Schizoaffective disorder",
      "C": "Simple schizophrenia",
      "D": "Paranoid schizophrenia",
      "E": "Residual schizophrenia"
    },
    "correct_answer": "B",
    "explanation": "The subtypes of schizophrenia have been eliminated from ICD-11, but schizoaffective disorder continues to be recognised."
  },
  {
    "number": 7,
    "question": "Which of the following is a qualier, an additional diagnostic descriptor, for depressive episodes in ICD-11?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Severe disturbance of functioning",
      "B": "Catatonia",
      "C": "Suicidal ideation",
      "D": "Melancholic features",
      "E": "Acute onset"
    },
    "correct_answer": "D",
    "explanation": "The qualiers for depressive episodes in ICD-11 are melancholic features, anxiety symptoms, panic attacks, and seasonal pattern."
  },
  {
    "number": 8,
    "question": "Which of the following is a new disorder in ICD-11 under the obsessive-compulsive and related disorders grouping?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Body integrity dysphoria",
      "B": "Avoidant/restrictive food intake disorder",
      "C": "Olfactory reference disorder",
      "D": "Gaming disorder",
      "E": "Bodily distress disorder"
    },
    "correct_answer": "C",
    "explanation": "Olfactory reference disorder is characterised by the persistent belief that one is emitting an offensive body odour or breath, which others cannot perceive."
  },
  {
    "number": 9,
    "question": "Malingering is the falsification or exaggeration of illness, either physical or mental, for the purpose of secondary gain. Under which diagnostic grouping is it placed in ICD-11?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Factitious disorders",
      "B": "Impulse control disorders",
      "C": "Factors influencing health status or contact with health services",
      "D": "Personality disorders",
      "E": "Disruptive behaviour and dissocial disorders"
    },
    "correct_answer": "C",
    "explanation": "Malingering is not categorised as a mental health condition under ICD-11, although is mentioned under factors influencing health status."
  },
  {
    "number": 10,
    "question": "The core concept of the paraphilic disorders in ICD-11 is that they involve sexual arousal that focuses upon non-consenting others. In which of the following scenarios would solitary acts or those involving consenting others meet the criteria for diagnosis?",
    "options": {
      "A": "If the individual takes on the role of another person as part of the behaviour",
      "B": "If the individual is very concerned about their partner rejecting them due to their behaviour",
      "C": "If the individual performs the acts outside of a private space",
      "D": "If the behaviour is potentially dangerous",
      "E": "If the individual would be embarrassed if their behaviour was discovered"
    },
    "correct_answer": "D",
    "explanation": "There is a category under paraphilic disorders which can be used if an individual's solitary acts or those with consenting others are associated with thoughts, fantasies, urges or behaviours which are very distressing or confer direct risk of injury or death."
  },
  {
    "number": 11,
    "question": "Which of the following is a change in the diagnostic criteria for anorexia nervosa in ICD-11?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Endocrine disturbance not necessary for diagnosis",
      "B": "Cross-listed with obsessive-compulsive and related disorders",
      "C": "Threshold BMI for diagnosis is now 18.5kg/m2",
      "D": "Fat phobia necessary for diagnosis",
      "E": "Specific behaviours for weight loss not mentioned"
    },
    "correct_answer": "A",
    "explanation": "Endocrine disturbance is no longer necessary for a diagnosis of anorexia nervosa in ICD-11."
  },
  {
    "number": 12,
    "question": "Which of the following is a new disorder in ICD-11, found under the obsessive-compulsive and related disorders diagnostic grouping?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Gaming disorder",
      "B": "Compulsive sexual behaviour disorder",
      "C": "Complex PTSD",
      "D": "Excoriation disorder",
      "E": "Hypochondriasis"
    },
    "correct_answer": "D",
    "explanation": "Excoriation disorder is characterised by repetitive picking at the skin, leading to lesions, and repeated but unsuccessful attempts to reduce the behaviour."
  },
  {
    "number": 13,
    "question": "How many groupings of diagnoses are there in the new ICD-11 chapter on mental, behavioural and neurodevelopmental disorders?",
    "options": { "A": "11", "B": "21", "C": "10", "D": "26", "E": "18" },
    "correct_answer": "B",
    "explanation": "There are 21 groupings in the ICD-11 chapter focusing on mental health disorders."
  },
  {
    "number": 14,
    "question": "Which of the following concepts is reflective of a change in ICD-11 (from ICD-10)?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Removal of minimum symptom count for all disorders",
      "B": "Introduction of gender incongruence as mental health disorder",
      "C": "All disorders can be diagnosed at any age",
      "D": "Cultural considerations have been removed",
      "E": "Use of dimensional approach for all disorders"
    },
    "correct_answer": "C",
    "explanation": "ICD-11 takes a lifespan approach to diagnosis, permitting diagnoses which were usually associated with childhood or adolescence to be diagnosed at any age."
  },
  {
    "number": 15,
    "question": "Which of the following is one of the maladaptive traits that can be used to further describe a diagnosis of personality disorder in ICD-11?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Mood variability",
      "B": "Anxiousness",
      "C": "Dissociality",
      "D": "Affective lability",
      "E": "Impulsivity"
    },
    "correct_answer": "C",
    "explanation": "The maladaptive traits that can be used to describe a diagnosis of personality disorder in ICD-11 are: negative affectivity, detachment, dissociality, disinhibition and anankastia."
  },
  {
    "number": 16,
    "question": "Which of the following is a new mental health disorder under ICD-11?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Acute stress reaction",
      "B": "Hyperkinetic disorder",
      "C": "Prolonged grief disorder",
      "D": "Trichotillomania",
      "E": "Sadomasochistic disorder"
    },
    "correct_answer": "C",
    "explanation": "Prolonged grief disorder is a new mental health disorder under ICD-11 categorised under disorders specifically associated with stress."
  },
  {
    "number": 17,
    "question": "In ICD-11, which of the following groupings includes a dimensional element for the diagnoses within it?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Catatonia",
      "B": "Disorders due to substance use and addictive behaviours",
      "C": "Schizophrenia and other primary psychotic disorders",
      "D": "Dissociative disorders",
      "E": "Anxiety and fear-related disorders"
    },
    "correct_answer": "C",
    "explanation": "Personality disorders and 'schizophrenia and other primary psychotic disorders' include significant dimensional elements to enable clearer descriptions of the symptomatology experienced by patients."
  }
]
